[{"id":"5d74d3d0-8a7e-11e8-8156-bd815d4e1d4e","question":"adoimplore","ans":[{"value":"To attempt (to do) something","isTrue":false},{"value":"without wasting more time;","isTrue":true},{"value":"a person who is killed or who suffers greatly for a religion, cause, etc.","isTrue":false},{"value":"causing a feeling of great surprise or wonder : causing astonishment","isTrue":false}],"examples":["And so, without further ado, let me introduce tonight's speaker","She implored her son not to go.","He implored her to think of the children."]},{"id":"5d7e70c0-8a7e-11e8-8156-bd815d4e1d4e","question":"comprehend","ans":[{"value":"to form an opinion or to make an estimate about something from known facts","isTrue":false},{"value":"to understand something completely, often bit difficult.","isTrue":true},{"value":"causing someone to become or feel less respected:","isTrue":false},{"value":"to support, strengthen, or defend (something)","isTrue":false}],"examples":["He is able to fully comprehend what is happening and react appropriately.","When you strive to comprehend your code, you create better work and become better at what you do"]},{"id":"5d7e70c1-8a7e-11e8-8156-bd815d4e1d4e","question":"exploitation","ans":[{"value":"causing a feeling of great surprise or wonder : causing astonishment","isTrue":false},{"value":"the act of using someone unfairly for your own advantage","isTrue":true},{"value":"An expression, often found in literature, that describes a person or object by referring to something that is considered to have similar characteristics to that person or object","isTrue":false},{"value":"the meaning and interpretation of words, signs and sentence structure.","isTrue":false}],"examples":["Exploitation of colonies leaves them at a disadvantage and makes the colonizing nations more wealthy and powerful."]},{"id":"5d7e97d0-8a7e-11e8-8156-bd815d4e1d4e","question":"metaphor","ans":[{"value":"to agree with someone or something","isTrue":false},{"value":"said or done in a forceful or definite way; resounding","isTrue":false},{"value":"the meaning and interpretation of words, signs and sentence structure.","isTrue":false},{"value":"An expression, often found in literature, that describes a person or object by referring to something that is considered to have similar characteristics to that person or object","isTrue":true}],"examples":["The mind is an ocean.","the city is a jungle."]},{"id":"5d7e97d1-8a7e-11e8-8156-bd815d4e1d4e","question":"preemptive","ans":[{"value":"done before someone else can do it","isTrue":true},{"value":"to support, strengthen, or defend (something)","isTrue":false},{"value":"to turn the pages of (a book, magazine, etc.) quickly","isTrue":false},{"value":"to drink quickly, eagerly, and usually in large amounts","isTrue":false}],"examples":["Just as Martha was about to take the only cookie left on the table, Noah preemptively swiped it."]},{"id":"5d7e97d2-8a7e-11e8-8156-bd815d4e1d4e","question":"taxing","ans":[{"value":"An expression, often found in literature, that describes a person or object by referring to something that is considered to have similar characteristics to that person or object","isTrue":false},{"value":"use to the limit; exhaust","isTrue":true},{"value":"to ignore (someone) in a deliberate and insulting way","isTrue":false},{"value":"a quality that makes one person or thing different from another","isTrue":false}],"examples":["The hike to the summit of Mt. Whitney was so taxing that I could barely speak or stand up."]},{"id":"5d7e97d3-8a7e-11e8-8156-bd815d4e1d4e","question":"disingenuous","ans":[{"value":"the suffering and death of a martyr.","isTrue":false},{"value":"not truly honest or sincere : giving the false appearance of being honest or sincere","isTrue":true},{"value":"a comparison of two things based on their being alike in some way","isTrue":false},{"value":"not clear in meaning; not thinking or expressing your thoughts clearly or precisely;","isTrue":false}],"examples":["That advertisement is demeaning to women.","Her statement demeans the hard work the group has done."]},{"id":"5d7e97d4-8a7e-11e8-8156-bd815d4e1d4e","question":"demeaning","ans":[{"value":"the act of using someone unfairly for your own advantage","isTrue":false},{"value":"not truly honest or sincere : giving the false appearance of being honest or sincere","isTrue":false},{"value":"easily broken, torn, etc. : not strong or solid","isTrue":false},{"value":"causing someone to become or feel less respected:","isTrue":true}],"examples":["That advertisement is demeaning to women.","Her statement demeans the hard work the group has done."]},{"id":"5d7e97d5-8a7e-11e8-8156-bd815d4e1d4e","question":"caveat","ans":[{"value":"causing someone to become or feel less respected:","isTrue":false},{"value":"use to the limit; exhaust","isTrue":false},{"value":"an warning that should be remembered when you are doing or thinking about something","isTrue":true},{"value":"a strong feeling of dislike or hatred","isTrue":false}],"examples":["His investment advice comes with a caveat: that the stock market is impossible to predict with absolute accuracy."]},{"id":"5d7e97d6-8a7e-11e8-8156-bd815d4e1d4e","question":"Nuance","ans":[{"value":"the meaning and interpretation of words, signs and sentence structure.","isTrue":false},{"value":"without wasting more time;","isTrue":false},{"value":"to ignore (someone) in a deliberate and insulting way","isTrue":false},{"value":"a very slight difference in appearance, meaning, sound, etc.","isTrue":true}],"examples":["Actors have to study the nuances of facial expression to show the whole range of emotions."]},{"id":"5d7e97d7-8a7e-11e8-8156-bd815d4e1d4e","question":"Rhetorical","ans":[{"value":"very harsh and critical","isTrue":false},{"value":"An expression, often found in literature, that describes a person or object by referring to something that is considered to have similar characteristics to that person or object","isTrue":false},{"value":"A question : asked in order to make a statement rather than to get an answer.","isTrue":true},{"value":"a situation in which many people behave or react in an extreme or uncontrolled way because of fear, anger, etc.","isTrue":false}],"examples":["\"Should we be leaving soon?” “Is that a rhetorical question?” [=is that a question you're asking as a way to say that we should be leaving soon?]","My question was rhetorical. I wasn't really expecting an answer."]},{"id":"5d7e97d8-8a7e-11e8-8156-bd815d4e1d4e","question":"Sparse","ans":[{"value":"causing a feeling of great surprise or wonder : causing astonishment","isTrue":false},{"value":"thinly dispersed or scattered.","isTrue":true},{"value":"the meaning and interpretation of words, signs and sentence structure.","isTrue":false},{"value":"causing someone to become or feel less respected:","isTrue":false}],"examples":["Areas of sparse population"]},{"id":"5d7e97d9-8a7e-11e8-8156-bd815d4e1d4e","question":"Emphatic","ans":[{"value":"said or done in a forceful or definite way; resounding","isTrue":true},{"value":"Literally meaning a lack of claim to knowledge. Generally is referring to a lack of claim to knowledge about the possible existence of god(s). But can be used for anything in general.","isTrue":false},{"value":"easily broken, torn, etc. : not strong or solid","isTrue":false},{"value":"very strongly felt; very great; absolute or complete","isTrue":false}],"examples":["Her answer was an emphatic “Yes!”","It was a emphatic victory."]},{"id":"5d7e97da-8a7e-11e8-8156-bd815d4e1d4e","question":"Flimsy","ans":[{"value":"a tall, thick stone or dirt wall that is built around a castle, town, etc., to protect it from attacks","isTrue":false},{"value":"Literally meaning a lack of claim to knowledge. Generally is referring to a lack of claim to knowledge about the possible existence of god(s). But can be used for anything in general.","isTrue":false},{"value":"not truly honest or sincere : giving the false appearance of being honest or sincere","isTrue":false},{"value":"easily broken, torn, etc. : not strong or solid","isTrue":true}],"examples":["They made a flimsy argument against me.","flimsy construction."]},{"id":"5d7e97db-8a7e-11e8-8156-bd815d4e1d4e","question":"Vague","ans":[{"value":"not clear in meaning; not thinking or expressing your thoughts clearly or precisely;","isTrue":true},{"value":"the action of passing through or across a place.; the carrying of people or things from one place to another.","isTrue":false},{"value":"to make (someone) do something by using force or threats","isTrue":false},{"value":"the advocacy of women's rights on the ground of the equality of the sexes.","isTrue":false}],"examples":["Millennial is an identity given to a broadly and vaguely defined group of people.","The instructions she left were vague and difficult to follow.","He gave only a vague answer.","The judges determined that the law was too vague to be fairly enforced.","When I asked him what they talked about, he was rather vague."]},{"id":"5d7e97dc-8a7e-11e8-8156-bd815d4e1d4e","question":"squiggly","ans":[{"value":"to support, strengthen, or defend (something)","isTrue":false},{"value":"a short line with many curves : a short, wavy line.","isTrue":true},{"value":"not truly honest or sincere : giving the false appearance of being honest or sincere","isTrue":false},{"value":"a strong feeling of dislike or hatred","isTrue":false}],"examples":["His handwriting looks like a bunch of squiggles."]},{"id":"5d7e97dd-8a7e-11e8-8156-bd815d4e1d4e","question":"agnostic","ans":[{"value":"to form an opinion or to make an estimate about something from known facts","isTrue":false},{"value":"to make (someone) do something by using force or threats","isTrue":false},{"value":"Literally meaning a lack of claim to knowledge. Generally is referring to a lack of claim to knowledge about the possible existence of god(s). But can be used for anything in general.","isTrue":true},{"value":"to cause an angry, harmful, or violent action or feeling","isTrue":false}],"examples":["With layer of separation, one layer could be agnostic of other.","Few are atheists or agnostics."]},{"id":"5d7e97de-8a7e-11e8-8156-bd815d4e1d4e","question":"analogy","ans":[{"value":"a comparison of two things based on their being alike in some way","isTrue":true},{"value":"An expression, often found in literature, that describes a person or object by referring to something that is considered to have similar characteristics to that person or object","isTrue":false},{"value":"not truly honest or sincere : giving the false appearance of being honest or sincere","isTrue":false},{"value":"very harsh and critical","isTrue":false}],"examples":["He drew/made an analogy between flying a kite and fishing."]},{"id":"5d7e97df-8a7e-11e8-8156-bd815d4e1d4e","question":"take a stab at (something)","ans":[{"value":"a comparison of two things based on their being alike in some way","isTrue":false},{"value":"a very slight difference in appearance, meaning, sound, etc.","isTrue":false},{"value":"said or done in a forceful or definite way; resounding","isTrue":false},{"value":"To attempt (to do) something","isTrue":true}],"examples":["Sure, I'll take a stab at it."],"code":"derived from idiom \"stab in the dark\", meaning an attempt at something with little guidance or hope of success"},{"id":"5d7e97e0-8a7e-11e8-8156-bd815d4e1d4e","question":"thumb through","ans":[{"value":"to turn the pages of (a book, magazine, etc.) quickly","isTrue":true},{"value":"the meaning and interpretation of words, signs and sentence structure.","isTrue":false},{"value":"To attempt (to do) something","isTrue":false},{"value":"causing a feeling of great surprise or wonder : causing astonishment","isTrue":false}],"examples":["I thumbed through a magazine while I waited."]},{"id":"5d7e97e1-8a7e-11e8-8156-bd815d4e1d4e","question":"Feminism or Feminist","ans":[{"value":"a situation in which many people behave or react in an extreme or uncontrolled way because of fear, anger, etc.","isTrue":false},{"value":"to drink quickly, eagerly, and usually in large amounts","isTrue":false},{"value":"causing a feeling of great surprise or wonder : causing astonishment","isTrue":false},{"value":"the advocacy of women's rights on the ground of the equality of the sexes.","isTrue":true}],"examples":["the feminist movement"]},{"id":"5d7e97e2-8a7e-11e8-8156-bd815d4e1d4e","question":"snub","ans":[{"value":"to ignore (someone) in a deliberate and insulting way","isTrue":true},{"value":"a quality that makes one person or thing different from another","isTrue":false},{"value":"a person who is killed or who suffers greatly for a religion, cause, etc.","isTrue":false},{"value":"to drink quickly, eagerly, and usually in large amounts","isTrue":false}],"examples":["She snubbed me in the hallway."]},{"id":"5d7e97e3-8a7e-11e8-8156-bd815d4e1d4e","question":"extrapolate","ans":[{"value":"thinly dispersed or scattered.","isTrue":false},{"value":"someone (such as a teacher or parent) who goes with children on a trip or to a school dance to make sure that the children behave properly","isTrue":false},{"value":"Literally meaning a lack of claim to knowledge. Generally is referring to a lack of claim to knowledge about the possible existence of god(s). But can be used for anything in general.","isTrue":false},{"value":"to form an opinion or to make an estimate about something from known facts","isTrue":true}],"examples":["We can extrapolate the number of new students entering next year by looking at how many entered in previous years.","With such a small study it is impossible to extrapolate accurately."]},{"id":"5d7e97e4-8a7e-11e8-8156-bd815d4e1d4e","question":"transit","ans":[{"value":"a strong feeling of dislike or hatred","isTrue":false},{"value":"the meaning and interpretation of words, signs and sentence structure.","isTrue":false},{"value":"the action of passing through or across a place.; the carrying of people or things from one place to another.","isTrue":true},{"value":"said or done in a forceful or definite way; resounding","isTrue":false}],"examples":["With transit visa, you can pass by country."]},{"id":"5d7e97e5-8a7e-11e8-8156-bd815d4e1d4e","question":"incite","ans":[{"value":"a short line with many curves : a short, wavy line.","isTrue":false},{"value":"to turn the pages of (a book, magazine, etc.) quickly","isTrue":false},{"value":"said or done in a forceful or definite way; resounding","isTrue":false},{"value":"to cause an angry, harmful, or violent action or feeling","isTrue":true}],"examples":["The victim had done nothing to incite [=provoke] the attackers.","They were clearly trying to incite the crowd to violence."]},{"id":"5d7e97e6-8a7e-11e8-8156-bd815d4e1d4e","question":"astonishing","ans":[{"value":"the action of passing through or across a place.; the carrying of people or things from one place to another.","isTrue":false},{"value":"causing a feeling of great surprise or wonder : causing astonishment","isTrue":true},{"value":"Literally meaning a lack of claim to knowledge. Generally is referring to a lack of claim to knowledge about the possible existence of god(s). But can be used for anything in general.","isTrue":false},{"value":"to make (someone) do something by using force or threats","isTrue":false}],"examples":["She gave an astonishing performance in her first film.","an astonishingly beautiful scene"]},{"id":"5d7e97e7-8a7e-11e8-8156-bd815d4e1d4e","question":"concur","ans":[{"value":"to agree with someone or something","isTrue":true},{"value":"the action of passing through or across a place.; the carrying of people or things from one place to another.","isTrue":false},{"value":"to understand something completely, often bit difficult.","isTrue":false},{"value":"causing someone to become or feel less respected:","isTrue":false}],"examples":["We concur that more money should be spent on education.","She concurred with the judge."]},{"id":"5d7e97e8-8a7e-11e8-8156-bd815d4e1d4e","question":"animosity","ans":[{"value":"to turn the pages of (a book, magazine, etc.) quickly","isTrue":false},{"value":"very strongly felt; very great; absolute or complete","isTrue":false},{"value":"causing someone to become or feel less respected:","isTrue":false},{"value":"a strong feeling of dislike or hatred","isTrue":true}],"examples":["There has always been animosity between India and Pakistan."]},{"id":"5d7e97e9-8a7e-11e8-8156-bd815d4e1d4e","question":"chaperone","ans":[{"value":"Literally meaning a lack of claim to knowledge. Generally is referring to a lack of claim to knowledge about the possible existence of god(s). But can be used for anything in general.","isTrue":false},{"value":"someone (such as a teacher or parent) who goes with children on a trip or to a school dance to make sure that the children behave properly","isTrue":true},{"value":"causing a feeling of great surprise or wonder : causing astonishment","isTrue":false},{"value":"To attempt (to do) something","isTrue":false}],"examples":["I was a chaperone on one of my son's school trips."]},{"id":"5d7e97ea-8a7e-11e8-8156-bd815d4e1d4e","question":"traits","ans":[{"value":"said or done in a forceful or definite way; resounding","isTrue":false},{"value":"a quality that makes one person or thing different from another","isTrue":true},{"value":"someone (such as a teacher or parent) who goes with children on a trip or to a school dance to make sure that the children behave properly","isTrue":false},{"value":"causing someone to become or feel less respected:","isTrue":false}],"examples":["Humility is an admirable trait."]},{"id":"5d7e97eb-8a7e-11e8-8156-bd815d4e1d4e","question":"martyrdom","ans":[{"value":"A question : asked in order to make a statement rather than to get an answer.","isTrue":false},{"value":"without wasting more time;","isTrue":false},{"value":"the suffering and death of a martyr.","isTrue":true},{"value":"the meaning and interpretation of words, signs and sentence structure.","isTrue":false}],"examples":["He suffered martyrdom for his religious beliefs."]},{"id":"5d7e97ec-8a7e-11e8-8156-bd815d4e1d4e","question":"martyr","ans":[{"value":"use to the limit; exhaust","isTrue":false},{"value":"to understand something completely, often bit difficult.","isTrue":false},{"value":"to drink quickly, eagerly, and usually in large amounts","isTrue":false},{"value":"a person who is killed or who suffers greatly for a religion, cause, etc.","isTrue":true}],"examples":["They know that killing him will only make a martyr out of him."]},{"id":"5d7e97ed-8a7e-11e8-8156-bd815d4e1d4e","question":"semantics","ans":[{"value":"a very slight difference in appearance, meaning, sound, etc.","isTrue":false},{"value":"easily broken, torn, etc. : not strong or solid","isTrue":false},{"value":"the meaning and interpretation of words, signs and sentence structure.","isTrue":true},{"value":"a tall, thick stone or dirt wall that is built around a castle, town, etc., to protect it from attacks","isTrue":false}],"examples":["The whole controversy is a matter of semantics."]},{"id":"5d7e97ee-8a7e-11e8-8156-bd815d4e1d4e","question":"guzzle","ans":[{"value":"very strongly felt; very great; absolute or complete","isTrue":false},{"value":"A question : asked in order to make a statement rather than to get an answer.","isTrue":false},{"value":"to drink quickly, eagerly, and usually in large amounts","isTrue":true},{"value":"a situation in which many people behave or react in an extreme or uncontrolled way because of fear, anger, etc.","isTrue":false}],"examples":["He guzzled his beer and ordered another.","Telecom business is a money guzzler."]},{"id":"5d7e97ef-8a7e-11e8-8156-bd815d4e1d4e","question":"snuggle","ans":[{"value":"an warning that should be remembered when you are doing or thinking about something","isTrue":false},{"value":"to turn the pages of (a book, magazine, etc.) quickly","isTrue":false},{"value":"to lie or sit close together in a comfortable position","isTrue":true},{"value":"without wasting more time;","isTrue":false}],"examples":["The puppy snuggled up against the sleeping boy.","The boy snuggled close to his mother."]},{"id":"5d7e97f0-8a7e-11e8-8156-bd815d4e1d4e","question":"hysteria","ans":[{"value":"to form an opinion or to make an estimate about something from known facts","isTrue":false},{"value":"a situation in which many people behave or react in an extreme or uncontrolled way because of fear, anger, etc.","isTrue":true},{"value":"An expression, often found in literature, that describes a person or object by referring to something that is considered to have similar characteristics to that person or object","isTrue":false},{"value":"a person who is killed or who suffers greatly for a religion, cause, etc.","isTrue":false}],"examples":["People were in hysteria after the death of their beloved actor.","A few of the children began to scream, and soon they were all caught up in the hysteria."]},{"id":"5d7e97f1-8a7e-11e8-8156-bd815d4e1d4e","question":"profound","ans":[{"value":"to agree with someone or something","isTrue":false},{"value":"to ignore (someone) in a deliberate and insulting way","isTrue":false},{"value":"to drink quickly, eagerly, and usually in large amounts","isTrue":false},{"value":"very strongly felt; very great; absolute or complete","isTrue":true}],"examples":["I profoundly apologize.","a profound silence.","a profound thinker."]},{"id":"5d7e97f2-8a7e-11e8-8156-bd815d4e1d4e","question":"coerce","ans":[{"value":"the act of using someone unfairly for your own advantage","isTrue":false},{"value":"the suffering and death of a martyr.","isTrue":false},{"value":"to make (someone) do something by using force or threats","isTrue":true},{"value":"causing someone to become or feel less respected:","isTrue":false}],"examples":["He was coerced into signing the confession.","Soldiers coerced the residents into giving them food.","The singer was coerced into a contract with the record company."]},{"id":"5d7e97f3-8a7e-11e8-8156-bd815d4e1d4e","question":"Atheist","ans":[{"value":"very strongly felt; very great; absolute or complete","isTrue":false},{"value":"As person who doesn't believe in god.","isTrue":true},{"value":"thinly dispersed or scattered.","isTrue":false},{"value":"the act of using someone unfairly for your own advantage","isTrue":false}]},{"id":"5d7e97f4-8a7e-11e8-8156-bd815d4e1d4e","question":"Caustic","ans":[{"value":"use to the limit; exhaust","isTrue":false},{"value":"a short line with many curves : a short, wavy line.","isTrue":false},{"value":"very harsh and critical","isTrue":true},{"value":"a situation in which many people behave or react in an extreme or uncontrolled way because of fear, anger, etc.","isTrue":false}],"examples":["caustic film reviews","She wrote a caustic report about the decisions that led to the crisis.","caustic humor/wit"]},{"id":"5d7e97f5-8a7e-11e8-8156-bd815d4e1d4e","question":"despair","ans":[{"value":"a person who is killed or who suffers greatly for a religion, cause, etc.","isTrue":false},{"value":"easily broken, torn, etc. : not strong or solid","isTrue":false},{"value":"to ignore (someone) in a deliberate and insulting way","isTrue":false},{"value":"the feeling of no longer having any hope","isTrue":true}],"examples":["His despair nearly drove him mad.","She let out a cry of despair. [=desperation]","I was overcome by despair at being unable to find them."]},{"id":"5d7e97f6-8a7e-11e8-8156-bd815d4e1d4e","question":"Buttress","ans":[{"value":"without wasting more time;","isTrue":false},{"value":"to turn the pages of (a book, magazine, etc.) quickly","isTrue":false},{"value":"done before someone else can do it","isTrue":false},{"value":"to support, strengthen, or defend (something)","isTrue":true}],"examples":["The treaty will buttress the cause of peace.","The theory has been buttressed by the results of the experiment."]},{"id":"5d7e97f7-8a7e-11e8-8156-bd815d4e1d4e","question":"Ramparts","ans":[{"value":"a tall, thick stone or dirt wall that is built around a castle, town, etc., to protect it from attacks","isTrue":true},{"value":"a comparison of two things based on their being alike in some way","isTrue":false},{"value":"not clear in meaning; not thinking or expressing your thoughts clearly or precisely;","isTrue":false},{"value":"a quality that makes one person or thing different from another","isTrue":false}],"examples":["The city's ramparts crumbled long ago."]}]